rebel wisdom released a video a couple
days ago
called the council god and in it they
talk about
this idea that council culture is
looking to cancel everything
you everyone doesn't matter how woke you
are because there's gonna be a tiny bit
of you that's not woke that what we're
doing is we're reacting to
our shadow and other people and trying
to cancel it when of course you can't
it's in you
it's everywhere it's like literally
trying to cancel your shadow
you can't do it so in the comments of
their video someone mentioned how
this canceled god reminds them of the
nothing from the neverending story
and so i got to thinking there's a
reason i'm bringing that up
i got to thinking about what does the
opposite of cancel culture look like
what does creation culture look like a
culture where everyone can try
and everyone succeeds to the point that
they're trying
and they keep they keep improving their
ideas keep improving
that is what creation culture gives us
and so i went for this walk and i had
the thought of the never ending story in
my head and
this scene at the end when sebastian's
reading the book
he doesn't know he's part of the story
he's just watching the heroes and
heroines and watching the story unfold
and the empress is begging for someone
to to do the thing those stories about
and she's crying out you know sebastian
say my name and he's like i can i have
to keep
both feet on the floor i can't
acknowledge that this this book
isn't just a book it's something real
and so when he finally gives in and gels
his mother's name
out of the window he's then transported
to fantasia
where the empress is sitting with the
last ember of fantasia
and he thinks everything's lost because
he failed there's only one little tiny
speck left
and she
just says you just need to wish fantasia
back like just make wish after wish
after wish and that will build fantasia
and so he brings back the planes and
betray you and and um
our tech and wishes to to go
in the sky on balco and and attack his
bullies
and this fantasy just being created and
that to me is creation culture not the
attacking of the bullies and not one
person having all the power but
realizing you have the power you also
have an ember
and the more we all have the nothing we
all the shadow side we all have the
ember which one are you going to focus
on
envision a world wink your wishes and
that is creation culture
what else creation culture is to me is
the opposite of cancel culture
so in council culture it's all about
broadcast media
even though it's more distributed it's
it's possible to get a youtube channel
with millions of subscribers
and so therefore anyone could kind of
have that happen unlike when someone had
to discover you and how that happened
for you to become famous you can become
youtube famous which actually can be
more
famous than hollywood famous and
in that in that it's become broadcast
it's like one person
and millions of followers which leaves
you more susceptible to the feeling of
being canceled
as the influencer it's also i've done
videos on all these topics
the difference between oxytocin and
dopamine that being an influencer is
attracting dopamine all about getting
people to like you and oxytocin's all
about giving love
it's like right you don't feel oxytocin
people love you you feel it when you
love other people
and so a culture of interconnection that
is that is
distributed where we feel connected
where you know you cannot fail
not because you can't get your idea
wrong or you're not going to make
mistakes
but you know you're not going to be
canceled over it you know there's a road
to redemption you know that the people
you've surrounded yourself with will see
you for you and everything you've been
beforehand
and allow you to redeem yourself and
there'll be a system of redemption
that the very big difference between
council culture which is not voluntary
right you don't get to choose to be
canceled
everyone else is and we didn't get
together decide on the rules for council
culture
it's like did the right people see you
at the wrong time doing the wrong thing
then you're canceled forever
and there's very few roads to redemption
to come back
so what would creation culture look like
how do we
have a world where anyone feels that
they can create something there's a
saying that
or a question the coaches ask which is
like if you
knew you couldn't fail what would you
try what would you do
write down jump off a building and fly
let me keep i knew i couldn't fail i
can't fall i'm doing some
mystical crap but the truth is it's like
okay well what does failure mean
is it financial failure isn't starving
to death and not having a roof over your
head is it social failure and feeling
alone and isolated
and together we can solve both of those
things so that no one has to worry
about cancel cancellation equaling death
because they don't worry they can't feed
their family in a roof over their head
and it doesn't mean social death either
that there's always someone to connect
with
and so i would like to hear from you
what do you think creation culture would
look like
what would yeah what would it look like
i have more thoughts on it but i want to
hear yours
so i will see you next time and
definitely check out wisdom
rebel wisdom's video i'll link it in the
description thanks